(お登勢)まったく…
あれから２週間➡
あのﾊﾞｶ どこ
ほっつき歩いてるんだろうねぇ｡
[Snack House Otose]
[Odd Jobs Gin-chan]
Honestly...
It's been two weeks. I wonder where that idiot has wandered off to.
[Gin-san's lost memories. They never came back in the end...]
[The Odd Jobs has been dissolved and Gin-san has gone missing. It isn't going to end like this, is it?]
[Resumé - Sagaru Yamazaki]
Umm... Yamazaki...
(ﾏﾑｼ)え～っと 山崎…｡
(ﾏﾑｼ)んっ？
これ なんて読むんだ？
How do you read this?
(山崎)ｻｶﾞﾙです 山崎 退｡
It's Sagaru. Sagaru Yamazaki.
《そう… ｵﾚの名は 山崎 退｡
Yes. My name is Sagaru Yamazaki.
泣く子も黙る
武装警察 真選組の 監察だ｡
I'm a spy for the Shinsengumi... The elite police force that makes even children go silent with fear.
そんなｵﾚが なぜ こんな工場に➡
So why have I come to this factory... And why for an interview?
面接に来ているかって？》
(ﾏﾑｼ)あっそ… おたくもﾘｽﾄﾗ｡
Oh. I see.
Lost your job, huh? Lately the town has been crawling with samurai who can't find jobs.
最近は 職にあぶれた侍で
街 あふれ返ってるもんな｡
《もちろん ﾘｽﾄﾗなんかじゃない｡
Of course, I have not lost my job. In fact, it's my job that brings me here.
ｵﾚが動くとき それは➡
事件のにおいを
かぎつけたときだけさ》
Long ago...
(ﾏﾑｼ)かくいうｵﾚも 昔は
腰に刀 差してたんだがね…➡
I once had a sword on my waist, too.
今は これさ｡
Now, look at me.
Well, there are a lot of...
まぁ ここは ｱﾝﾀみたいな
落武者たちが たくさんいる｡
Fallen samurai like you here. Make friends with them, okay?
(ﾏﾑｼ)似た者どうし
仲よくやってくれ｡
おい！ みんな 新入りだぞ｡
Hey.
Everyone, we've got a newcomer.
(銀時)うぃ～っす…｡
["Life Moves On Like a Conveyor Belt"]
What?!
いぃ～っ!? 万事屋の旦那！
You're from the Odd Jobs!
ｱﾝﾀ なんで こんなところに？
What are you doing in a place like this?!
ｵﾚですよ ｵﾚ！ 真選組の山崎です｡
It's me. Yamazaki of the Shinsengumi.
実は 訳あって 潜入捜査で
ここに潜り込んだんですがね…｡
Actually, due to certain circumstances, I've snuck into this place to do an undercover investigation.
(ﾏﾑｼ)おい 言っとくけど ｿｲﾂ➡
Hey. Just to let you know, he has amnesia and doesn't know anything about his past.
記憶喪失で 昔のこと
なんも覚えてねえぞ｡
記憶喪失!?
Amnesia?!
That's the case. Sorry.
そういうことなんで すみません｡
旧知のようですが
ﾎﾞｸは 覚えてないんで…｡
You seem to be an old acquaintance, but I don't remember you.
えっと 真選組の何？
Umm, what's the Shinsengumi? Can I call you Shin-chan?
真ちゃんとか 呼べばいいかな？
Hold on! I told you that this is an undercover investigation.
ちょっと！
潜入捜査って 言ってるでしょ!!
あっ！ 言っちゃった…｡
Oh. I said it out loud!!
なんですか？ ｱﾝﾀ…｡
Why do you keep hitting my head?
人の頭 ﾊﾟﾝﾊﾟﾝ ﾊﾟﾝﾊﾟﾝ…
ﾀﾝﾊﾞﾘﾝ奏者気取りですか？
Do you think you're a tambourine player?
真ちゃんがｲﾔなら➡
If you don't like Shin-chan, then how about Sen-chan for undercover investigation?
潜入捜査の 潜ちゃんとか
どうですか？
Are you trying to annoy me? I told you! I'm Yamazaki.
(山崎)嫌がらせ？
山崎って 言ってるでしょ！
I don't remember you, so I'll call you Tamboura.
いや 覚えてないんで ﾀﾝﾊﾞﾗｰで…｡
You don't remember? You don't even want to remember!
(山崎)覚えてないっつうか
覚える気 ねえじゃねえか！
そういや ｷｬﾗも いつもと違うし
目も死んでない…｡
Come to think of it, you're acting different than usual and your eyes aren't lifeless.
えっ？ でも 万事屋は？
Huh? But what happened to the Odd Jobs?
(山崎)他の連中は
どうしたんですか？
What happened to everyone else?
万事屋は…｡
The Odd Jobs...
(新八)神楽ちゃん
また ここに来てたの？
Kagura-chan...
You came here again? I told you it's dangerous. This place could come tumbling down...
この家 いつ崩れるか
わからないから➡
危ないって言ったろ？
さっ ｳﾁに戻ろう｡
Come on, let's go home. Sis and Sadaharu are waiting.
姉上も 定春も 待ってるよ｡
(酢こんぶを食べる音)
いいかげんにしろぉ！
ﾎﾟﾘﾎﾟﾘﾎﾟﾘﾎﾟﾘ ﾎﾟﾘﾎﾟﾘﾎﾟﾘﾎﾟﾘ!!
Will you quit with the nibble-nibbling, already?! Is your name Ohori?!
お堀さんか お前は！
What do you plan to do with all that pickled seaweed?!
そんなに酢こんぶ 買い込んで
なにするつもりだ！
(酢こんぶを食べる音)
Kagura-chan, don't tell me you're planning to sit here until Gin-san comes back?
ひょっとして 神楽ちゃん…➡
銀さんが 帰ってくるまで
ここで待ってるつもりなの？
(酢こんぶを食べる音)
The doctor was saying a person's memory is like intertwined branches.
お医者さんが 言ってたよね｡
人の記憶は 木の枝のように
複雑に入り組んでいるって…｡
だから 木の枝 １本でも
ざわめかせれば➡
If one of the branches is moved, the others will start to move too.
他の枝も
動き始めるかもしれないって…｡
でも もし 木そのものが
枯れてしまっていたら…｡
But if that tree has withered...Then its branches may just fall off.
もう 枝なんて落ちて➡
なくなってしまっているかも
しれない…｡
ﾎﾞｸらみたいな 小枝なんて
銀さんは もう…｡
Gin-san doesn't remember little branches like us...
(神楽)枯れてないよ！
He hasn't withered.
枯れさせないよ…
私たち 小枝かもしれない｡
I won't let him wither.
We may be little branches...but if the branches break, then the tree really will wither.
でも 枝が折れてしまったら
ﾎﾝﾄに 木も枯れちゃうよ…｡
(神楽)だから 私 折れないね｡
So I won't break.
Even if winter comes and the leaves fall off.
冬がきて 葉が落ちても➡
Even if the wind blows and all the other branches fall down, I'll be the last branch of all!
風が吹いて
枝が みんな落ちても➡
私は 最後の１本になっても
折れないね｡
I'll stick with the tree until the very end!
最後まで きっと一緒にいるね｡
♪♪～
He'd damn well better come back.
ﾎﾝﾄに 戻ってくるんだろうなぁ
あの ちゃらんぽらん…｡
早くしないと ﾎﾞｸら➡
If he doesn't hurry our crap's gonna start turning green.
緑色のｳﾝｺ
出るようになっちゃうよ｡
Hey, don't eat that without my permission!
(神楽)ﾃﾒｴ… なに
勝手に食ってんだぁ～！
ぎゃあぁ～っ!!
Oh my.
(お登勢)おやおや… うるさいのが
ようやく消えたと思ったら➡
I thought all the noisy ones finally disappeared. So you're still here?
まだ いたのかい？
This could be a problem. See, I want to tear down the second floor right away.
困るんだけどねぇ…
こんなことになった以上➡
さっさと ２階
取り壊しちまいたいからさぁ…｡
待ってよ！ 私たち 必ず
銀ちゃん 連れ戻してくるから!!
Wait. We'll bring back Gin-chan.
連れ戻すって… 野郎の
居場所も知らないのにかい？
You'll bring him back? Do you even know where he is?
I heard a man with silver hair is working as a live-in at this factory.
(お登勢)
そこの住所にある工場で➡
最近 銀髪の男が
住み込みで働いているそうだ｡
(お登勢)さっさと
引きずってきな！
Go bring him back quick.
He still owes me rent.
たまった家賃…
払ってもらわないと 困るんでね｡
[Mamushi Factory]
(ﾏﾑｼ)おい ﾃﾒｴ！
なにやってんだ!!
Hey! What are you doing?
(ﾏﾑｼ)こういう流れ作業は
１人がﾐｽったら➡
If one person on the assembly line makes a mistake, the whole line stops!
ﾗｲﾝが全部 止まっちまうんだよ！
S-Sorry.
す… すみません｡
(ﾏﾑｼ)すみませんじゃねえよ！
Sorry won't cut it. I keep telling you the same thing. It's easy.
(ﾏﾑｼ)ﾃﾒｴよぉ 何度も同じこと
言わせやがって！
(ﾏﾑｼ)簡単だろうが！
こんなもんよぉ➡
It's like this! You put this here and assemble it!
これを ここに乗せて ｺｲﾂを
立てれば いいだけだろうが！
Anyway, what are we making? What does this factory produce?
(山崎)ていうか… これ
何を作ってるんですか？
(山崎)この工場
何を生産してるんですか？
あれだよ お前…
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲに 決まってんだろうが｡
It's obvious. Justaways dolls, of course!
(山崎)だから ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲって
何だって 聞いてんだろうが！
I'm asking you what a "Justaway" is!
(ﾏﾑｼ)ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲは ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ以外の
何物でもない｡
A Justaway is a Justaway. Nothing else. Nothing more, nothing less.
(ﾏﾑｼ)それ以上でも
それ以下でもない！
ただの ｶﾞﾗｸﾀじゃないか！
But it's just a piece of junk! How am I supposed to care about making one!
労働意欲が 失せるんだよ！
なんか これ見てると!!
ﾃﾒｴらは 無心に ただひたすら
手ぇ動かしてればいいんだよ｡
Look. All you have to do is empty your mind and move your hands.
見ろ 坂田を｡
Check out Sakata.
Wow! He's incredibly fast!
(従業員)うおぉ すっげ はえぇ！
As expected of Sakata-san. He rolls out Justaways so fast you can't even see 'em!
(従業員)さすが 坂田さんだ…｡
ものすごい勢いで
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲが 量産されていく！
次期工場長は ﾔﾂしかいねえな｡
At this rate, he'll make vice-president inside a year!
(ﾏﾑｼ)みんなも
負けないように がんばれ｡
Everyone, try not to lose to him!
(従業員たち)うぉ～っ！
All right!
They hire vice-presidents based on assembly line speed? This place is doomed!
(山崎)そんなんで
工場長 決まるの!?
(山崎)おしまいだ…
ここ おしまいだよ！
No, I still haven't found anything out. Yes...
はい… こっちは まだ
何も つかめてませんが…｡
はい… いっ!? ﾏｼﾞすか！
Really?! All right. I'll head back right away.
わかりました…
すぐ 戻りますんで｡
旦那… ｵﾚ もう
ここ引き揚げます｡
I'm checking out of here. Apparently, Chief Kondo has gone missing.
局長が 行方不明に
なってるらしくて｡
ｼﾞﾐｰ… あれくらいで
へこたれるのかよ！
Jimmy, you can't abandon your Justaways just for that.
誰だって 最初は うまくいかない｡
Nobody does well in the beginning. You'll get used to things.
人間 なんでも慣れさ｡
(山崎)ｼﾞﾐｰって誰!?
Who's Jimmy?! Are you saying I'm boring? Anyway, I was only here to spy!
(山崎)それは もしかして
地味から きてるのか？
それから ｵﾚは
密偵で来てるだけだから！
はぁ… 旦那も 早いとこ➡
I think you should leave this place as soon as possible.
引き払ったほうが
いいと思いますよ｡
There are some dark rumors about the plant Boss.
ここの工場長… 何かと
黒いｳﾜｻの絶えない野郎でね｡
(山崎)巷じゃ 職にあぶれた
浪人を雇ってくれる➡
To the public, he's a humanitarian taking care of down-and-out samurai who can't find jobs.
人情派で 通ってるらしいが➡
But it's rumored that he actually shelters rebel fighters
その実は 攘夷志士を囲い
幕府を転覆せんと➡
until he can carry out his plan to overthrow the government.
企ててると ｳﾜｻされてるんです｡
(山崎)他にも この工場の裏で➡
This factory is actually building weapons to supply the rebels.
攘夷浪士の武器を
製造しているとか➡
近く 大量殺戮兵器を用いて➡
And now he's preparing a weapon of mass destruction.
大きな騒ぎを
起こそうとしているとか➡
There aren't any good rumors about him.
ﾛｸなｳﾜｻがない…｡
(山崎)まっ 結果 こんなもんしか
出てきませんでしたが➡
Well, in the end, this is the only thing I found...
火のないところに
煙はたたないというし…｡
But as they say, "where's there's smoke, there's fire"...
おやっさんが ｴﾛﾘｽﾄだと!?
Are you saying that he's an erowrist?! I mean terrorist?
いいがかりは やめろ！
Stop making up excuses!
That man is my benefactor. It takes balls to hire down-and-outers like me!
おやっさんはな
ﾎﾞｸを拾ってくれた恩人だぞ！
なに言ってるか わかりませんけど
ｴﾛですか？ ﾘｽﾄなんですか？
I don't think it takes balls.
More like a maniacal scheme running off slave labor.
っていうか 旦那
どうしちゃったんですか？
Anyway, what happened to you?
ﾎﾞｸは 以前の 堕落した自分は
受け入れられない｡
I was just a worthless degenerate before I got this job.
生き直そうと 心に決めたんだ｡
旦那…｡
Boss...
(山崎)そうですか｡
ちょっと残念な気もしますが…｡
Is that so? I'm a little disappointed.
ｱﾝﾀ 確かに 一見 ただの
ちゃらんぽらんでしたがね➡
I mean, not about you being a degenerate. That's obvious.
But Chief Kondo and Vice-chief Okita obviously respect you.
局長も 沖田隊長も
一目置いているようだったので…｡
(近藤)坂田さん
仕事 始まりますよ｡
Sakata-san, work's about to start.
Oh no.
おっと いけねえ｡
じゃあ これで ｵﾚは…｡
I'll be off...
(近藤)坂田さん ちょっと
ﾎﾞｸの ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ 見てくれませんか？
Sakata-san, could you look at my Justaway?
(近藤)どうですかね？ これ｡
What do you think of it?
Well, I think you should lift this up just a bit, Gorilla-san.
そうだねぇ…
もうちょっと ここを➡
きもち 上げたほうがいいかな
ｺﾞﾘさん｡
お前 なにしてんの～っ!?
Have you lost your frikiking mind?!
ｺﾞﾘさ～ん！
Gorilla-san!
もしも～し ﾊﾞｶ 発見しました｡
えぇ すぐ 連れて帰りますんで｡
Hello? I found the idiot. Yes. I'm taking him back right away.
Gorilla-san, get a hold of yourself!
ｺﾞﾘさん しっかりしろ！
ｼﾞﾐｰ なんてﾏﾈするんだ！
Jimmy, what was that for?!
Gorilla-san is another amnesia victim!
ｺﾞﾘさんはな ﾎﾞｸと同じように
記憶を失っていて➡
頭は ﾃﾞﾘｹｰﾄに扱ってやらないと
すぐ とぶんだ！
His brain's like a cheap game console! Bump it and it freezes!
初期の ﾌｧﾐｺﾝなみなんだぞ！
記憶喪失!? ﾏｼﾞですか 局長！
Amnesia?! Is that true, Chief?!
(山崎)ｱﾝﾀ ﾊﾞｶのくせに➡
You're an idiot, but why have you got such a complicated condition?!
なに ややこしい症状に
見舞われてんの！
You're such an idiot!
(山崎)ﾊﾞｶのくせに!!
言い過ぎだぞ ｼﾞﾐｰ！
That's going overboard, Jimmy. Idiots, in their own idiotic way, have their own idiotic problems!
ﾊﾞｶは ﾊﾞｶなりに
ﾊﾞｶな悩み 抱えてんだ！
(山崎)うるせえよ！
もう だりいよ！
Shut up. I'm tired. You two are such a pain.
(山崎)めんどくせえよ ｵﾒｴら！
(近藤)ひぃっ！
(山崎)とにかく
一緒に帰りますよ 局長！
Anyway, we're going home, Chief!
やめろ！ ﾎﾞｸは 江戸一番の➡
Stop! I still have to fix my Justaway!!
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ職人になるって
決めたんだ！
I want people to be proud of me! I want to be special!!
なんでもいいから１番になるって
おやっさんと約束したんだ！
It doesn't matter what it is, but I promised pops I was going to become number one.
(山崎)だったら 安心しろ｡
お前は 世界一のﾊﾞｶだ｡
Then don't worry. You're the world's biggest idiot.
(山崎)さぁ 早く｡
(近藤)ｲﾔだ！ ｲﾔだ！
Come on. Quickly!
No! No!
(近藤)あっ｡
(爆発音)
(従業員)わぁ～っ 爆発だぁ！
An explosion!
工場長！ ｺｲﾂは
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲが 暴発したんじゃ!?
Boss, did a Justaway accidentally go off?
誰だ こんなﾏﾈしたﾔﾂは！
Who is responsible for this?!
(銀時たち)あぁぁ～～っ!!
No way!
ｳｿ！ ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲが!?
The Justaway exploded!!
そんな！ ﾎﾞｸら
爆弾を作らされていたってのか!?
No way! We were making bombs?!
なんてこった
まさか ﾎﾝﾄに おやっさんが…｡
This is terrible... Did pops really do this?
確かに 幕府のせいで
ﾘｽﾄﾗされたとか ｸﾞﾁってたけど➡
He griped a lot about losing his job because of the government and swore vengeance, but...
まさか！
(山崎)まさかじゃねえよ！
Of course it's him! These are all top grade ingredients!
超一流の食材
揃ってるじゃないすか！
豪華ﾃﾞｨﾅｰが 出来上がるよ！
What about it can't you believe?
(近藤)悪いのは
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲではない！
It's not the Justaway's fault! That man was bad.
悪いのは おやっさんであって
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲに 罪はない！
The Justaways have done no wrong.
(山崎)
局長～！ まだ持ってたんすか！
Are you still carrying those? Get rid of them right away!!
(山崎)早く捨てて!!
(ﾏﾑｼたち)うおぉ～っ！
You bastards! How dare you ruin my plans!
ﾃﾒｴらか！ よくも ｵﾚの計画
台なしにしてくれたな！
ｽﾊﾟｲどもが！ 血祭りじゃ!!
I'm going to slaughter you spies!
げぇっ！ おやっさん 来たぞ!!
Ack! Pops is headed this way!
ｼﾞﾐｰ こっちだ！
Jimmy, this way.
You're not getting away from me!!
逃がすかぁ～っ!!
(爆発音)
おい～！
やりあえないんじゃなかったの!?
Hey! I thought you couldn't fight him! But you didn't hesitate there!
おもっくそ
やっちゃったじゃないか!!
そんなこと言ったか？ ｺﾞﾘさん｡
Did I say that, Gorilla-san?
It's no good. I can't remember. I have amnesia.
ﾀﾞﾒだ 思い出せない｡
記憶喪失だから｡
(山崎)便利な記憶喪失だな おい！
What a convenient form of amnesia!
ﾌﾌﾌﾌ… 動くんじゃねえぞ｡
Don't move.
(ﾏﾑｼ)残念だったなぁ｡
Too bad.
(ﾏﾑｼ)こう見えても かつては
同心として 悪党を追い回し➡
Though I may not look it, I used to chase crooks as a police officer.
ﾏﾑｼの蛮蔵と呼ばれてたのさ｡
They called me Banzo the Viper.
You got me pretty good. I never thought that you were government spies.
(ﾏﾑｼ)やってくれたじゃねえか｡
(ﾏﾑｼ)まさか ﾃﾒｴらが
幕府の犬だったとはな｡
(ﾏﾑｼ)もう少しで ﾔﾂらに
目に物見せることができたのに…｡
Just a little longer and I would have taught them all a lesson.
だが こうなったら やってやるぜ｡
But now that this has happened,
腐った世の中
ひっくり返してやらぁ｡
I still have the power to turn this rotten world upside down.
(爆発音)
(沖田)は～い
危ないから 下がりなさい｡
All right, step back. It's dangerous. You'll end up like him.
この人のようになるよ｡
ﾎﾟｰｶｰﾌｪｲｽを気取ってるが➡
He doesn't look hurt, but trust me he's suffering inside.
ものっそい痛いんだよ｡
恥ずかしいんだよ｡
(土方)えらいことになってるな｡
Hell of a mess that turned out to be.
(沖田)土方さんも
えらいことになってますぜ｡
You're pretty messy too.
You think that jerk Yamazaki died in that?
(沖田)これ 山崎の野郎
死んだんじゃねえのか？
(沖田)土方さんも
死ぬんじゃないですか？
I'll bet you're going to die, too, aren't you?
(原田)副長！
(土方)ん？
Vice-chief!
We just got word that the Chief is inside with Yamazaki.
今 情報が入りまして
山崎と一緒に➡
局長も この中にいます｡
なんだと？
What?
おいおい 山崎１人なら
見捨てようかと思ったが➡
Come on. If it was just Yamazaki, I was going to say forget it.
近藤さんがいたんじゃ
そうもいかねえな｡
But I can't do that if Kondo-san is with him.
Hijikata-san...
(沖田)土方さん
ｵﾚ 笛 家に忘れたんで➡
I forgot my flute at home. I'm going to go and fetch it.
ちょっと 取りに帰ってきまさぁ｡
Okay. Don't come back.
あぁ 二度と戻ってくるな｡
(土方)ったく 情けねえ｡
もういい！
Jeez. How pathetic. That's enough. I'll go by myself. You all wait here.
(土方)ｵﾚ１人で行ってくるから
ﾃﾒｴらは そこで待ってろ｡
(隊士)おい あれ 見ろ！
Hey!! Look over there!
Something's coming out.
(隊士)何か出てきたぞ！
(原田)なんだ ありゃ！
What's that?
(隊士)大砲!?
ﾊﾞｶでけえ大砲が 出てきやがった！
A cannon?! A big-ass cannon came out!
あ… あれが
連中が 秘密裏に作っていた兵器!?
T-That's the weapon they were secretly building?
総悟 ｵﾚ 分度器 家に忘れたから
ちょっと 取りに帰ってくる｡
Sogo, I forgot my protractor at home. I'm going to go and fetch it.
(沖田)土方さん 大丈夫でさぁ｡
分度器なら ここにあります｡
Hijikata-san, it's all right. I have a protractor right here.
♪♪～
(太助)｢10月６日｡
October 6. Today, my father hit me for the first time.
今日 生まれて初めて
親父に殴られた｡
重い拳だった｡
It was a hard punch.
それは 己の背中ひとつで➡
It was a punch from a man who shouldered
ｵﾚたち家族や さまざまな重責を
負って生きてきた➡
our family and many important responsibilities on his back.
男の拳だった｡
My pitiful little fist couldn't have hit like that.
自分の拳が ひどく小さく見えた｡
仕事を辞め ２年と３か月｡
It was the punch of a loser who quit his job
ｹﾞｰﾑ機のｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾗｰしか
握ってこなかった 負け犬の拳だ｣
and never held anything but a game console controller for two years and three months.
((ﾏﾑｼ:別にな
上手に生きなくたっていいんだよ｡
I don't care what you do with your life.
恥をかこうが 泥にまみれようが
いいじゃねえか｡
You've got to live with yourself.
Just understand this: If you wallow in crap, you're going to stink.
最高の酒の肴だ ﾊﾞｶ野郎))
(太助)｢そう吐き捨てて
仕事に出かけた親父の背中は➡
As he left for work after saying these words, his shoulders looked broader to me than ever before.
いつもより大きく見えた｡
今からでも ｵﾚは
親父のようになれるだろうか？
Could I become strong like my father?
２年ぶりに 外に出た｡
I went outside for the first time in two years.
My legs naturally followed my father.
しぜんと親父を追う ｵﾚの足｡
ﾏﾑｼの蛮蔵…
それが 親父の もう１つの名前｡
Banzo the Viper. That was my father's other name.
悪党どもを震え上がらせる
同心 ﾏﾑｼ｡
Mamushi, a police officer who made criminals tremble.
彼の顔が見たかった｡
I wanted to see his face. I wanted to learn what it was to know him.
働くということが
どういうことなのか➡
彼を通して 知ろうと思った｣
But all I saw...was a beaten man with a cheap sake bottle in his hands.
(太助)｢ﾏﾑｼは ｶｯﾌﾟ酒 片手に➡
１日じゅう
公園で うなだれていた｡
He'd lost his job to downsizing the month before.
ﾏﾑｼは １か月前に ﾘｽﾄﾗ｣
No!!
ｲﾔ～～ｯ!!
(ﾏﾑｼ)お前らに わかるか
この ﾏﾑｼの気持が！
You can't imagine how that felt!
息子の日記に こんなこと書かれた
かわいそうなﾏﾑｼの気持が!!
How it felt to read my son's diary!!
(ﾏﾑｼ)もう少しだったんだ…
あとちょっとで➡
If I'd kept my job just a little longer, he would have straightened out his life!
息子も更正できたのに
ﾘｽﾄﾗは ねえだろ！
Instead, my son went from being a recluse to becoming a yakuza!
おかげで お前 息子は
ひきこもりからﾔｰさんに転職だよ｡
He's gone from the north pole to the south pole.
北極から南極だよ お前！
最高の酒の肴じゃねえか！
That's a great thing to talk about over drinks.
(ﾏﾑｼ)飲み込めるか！
でかすぎて 胃が もたれるわ!!
Am I supposed to take that and keep smiling?
(ﾏﾑｼ)こちとら
30年も お上のために➡
I devoted thirty years of my life to my country,
滅私奉公してきたってえのに➡
幕府も家族も
あっさり ｵﾚをﾎﾟｲ捨てだぜ！
but my family and the government dumped me like I was garbage!
There's something wrong! There's something wrong with this world!
間違ってる…
こんな世の中 間違ってる！
だから ｵﾚが変える！
So I'm going to change it!!
(ﾏﾑｼ)10年かけて造り上げた
この ﾏﾑｼＺで➡
I'm going to destroy this corrupt country and
腐った この国 ぶっ壊して
革命を起こしてやるのよ!!
cause a revolution with this Viper Z that took me ten years to make!
腐った国だろうが➡
It's a corrupt country, but you mustn't forget that people live here.
そこに暮らしてる連中がいるのを
忘れてもらっちゃ困る｡
Before you start a revolution in this country, why don't you start one within yourself?
革命なら 国に起こす前に
まず 自分に起こしたらどうだ？
That's a lot cheaper.
そのほうが安上がりだぜ｡
Shut up! You can't understand how I feel!
うるせえ！ ﾃﾒｴに
ｵﾚの気持が わかってたまるか!!
大砲 用意｡
Ready the cannon.
いや そこじゃなくて｡
えぇ!?
No, not that way.
なに ﾋﾞｯｸﾘしてんだ！
こっちが ﾋﾞｯｸﾘだわ!!
Why are you surprised?! I'm the one who should be surprised!
(原田)副長！ あ… あれ！
え？
Vice-chief!! Isn't that...
(土方)局長！ 山崎！
あれ？ なんで ｱｲﾂもいるんだ？
Chief! Yamazaki! Huh?! Why is that guy there, too?
(ﾏﾑｼ)ﾍｯﾍﾍ… ｺｲﾂらが ﾃﾒｴらの
仲間だってことは わかってる｡
I know that... They're your friends.
ｵﾚたちを止めたくば 撃つがいい｡
Shoot if you want to stop me. But they'll be blown to bits, too.
ｺｲﾂらも こっぱみじんだがな！
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ…！
(土方)総悟～!!
(砲撃音)
Sogo!
昔 近藤さんがねぇ…➡
Long ago, Kondo may or may not have said that if he was caught by an enemy
もし ｵﾚが
敵に捕まることがあったら➡
迷わず ｵﾚを撃てって➡
to shoot without hesitation.
言ってたような
言わなかったような｡
そんな
ｱﾊﾞｳﾄな理由で撃ったんかい！
You fired at them because of a perfunctory reason like that?!
撃ったぁ～！
撃ちやがったよ ｱｲﾂら～!!
They fired! They fired at us!
何ですか？ あの人たち！
Who are those people?! I thought you said they were your friends?!
ﾎﾝﾄに
あなたたちの仲間なんですか!?
(山崎)仲間じゃねえよ あんなん！
They're not my friends!
局長！ ｵﾚ もう辞めますから！
Chief, I'm going to quit the Shinsengumi. Huh? Where's the Chief?
真選組なんて… あれ？ 局長？
おぅ ここだ｡
みんな ｹｶﾞはないか？ 大丈夫か？
Hey. Over here. Is everyone safe? Are you all right?
Chief, are you all right?!
(山崎)局長！
ｱﾝﾀが大丈夫ですか!?
It's as if I've just awakened from a long dream.
(近藤)まるで
長い夢でも見ていたようだ｡
局長 まさか記憶が…
っていうか 頭！
Chief, could it be that your memories have returned?
Uh, your head...!
あぁ まるで
心の霧が晴れたような➡
Yes. It's as if the fog has cleared from my mind.
すがすがしい気分だよ｡
It's refreshing. Yamazaki, it seems I caused you a lot of trouble.
山崎！ いろいろ
迷惑かけたみたいだな｡
(山崎)いえ… っていうか 頭｡
Not really. But, your head...
(近藤)とにもかくにも
今は 逃げるのが先決だ｡ 行くぞ！
Anyway, right now, it's time for us to get out of here. Let's go.
Chief! Wait!
局長 待ってください！
まだ旦那が！
He's still...
いい… 行ってくれ ｼﾞﾐｰ ｺﾞﾘさん｡
It's all right. Go, Jimmy, Gorilla-san.
早くしないと 連中が来るぞ｡
Clear out before they catch you.
ﾁｯ！
Such a pain! Normally, I'd just leave you, but you've done no wrong!
(近藤)ｸｿｯﾀﾚ！ ふだんのお前なら
放っておくところだが➡
坂田さんに 罪はない！
記憶が戻ったら
なんか おごれよ ﾃﾒｴ～!!
Buy me a beer when you get your memory back.
《ｺﾞﾘさん…》
Gorilla-san...
(従業員)あっ なにやってんだ!?
えっ？
Hey! What are you doing?
うぉお～!!
(みんな)うわぁ～っ!!
Now! Fire!!
今だ 撃て～!!
(砲撃音)
(爆発音)
(従業員)工場長！
(ﾏﾑｼ)撃て！ ﾏﾑｼＺだぁ！
Boss!!
Fire! Use the... Viper Z!
(砲撃音)
(銀時たち)うわぁ～～!!
(近藤)ｸｿｯ！ てやぁ～!!
Crap!!
(山崎)局長～!!
(爆発音)
Chief!!
(土方)おい みんな 生きてるか？
Hey, is everyone still alive?
(沖田)ｺｲﾂは とんでもねえ｡
This thing is insane.
ﾎﾝﾄに 国くらい
消しちまいそうな威力だ｡
It seems like it has enough power to really be able to wipe out the country.
Chief!
(山崎)局長！ 局長
しっかりしてください！
Chief, get a hold of yourself!
局長！ 局長！ 局長～!!
Chief! Chief!
Chief!
(ﾏﾑｼ)見たか ﾏﾑｼＺの威力を！
Did you see the power of the Viper Z?! With this, Edo will be scorched in an instant.
これがあれば 江戸なんぞ
あっという間に焦土と化す！
止められるもんなら
止めてみろ～!!
Go ahead! Just try to stop me!
時代に迎合した お前ら軟弱な侍に
止められるものならよ～！
You weak samurai who have adjusted to the times cannot stop me!
さぁ 来いよ！
早くしねえと 次 撃っちまうよ！
Come on! If you don't hurry, I'll force my next shot.
Everyone's Edo will become a scorched field!
みんなの江戸が焼け野原だ！
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ…！ どうした？
What's wrong? Are you frozen in fear? How pathetic.
体がこわばって
動くこともできねえのか？
情けねえ！
If you want to shoot, be our guest.
どうぞ
撃ちたきゃ 撃ってください！
(神楽)江戸が焼けようが
煮られようが➡
We don't care if you fry or boil Edo.
知ったこっちゃないね！
でも この人だけは➡
You just better not shoot these people.
撃っちゃ困りますよ！
Wh-Who are you?! This isn't a place for kids!
(ﾏﾑｼ)なっ なんだ ﾃﾒｴら！
ここは ｶﾞｷの来る所じゃねえ！
帰れ！
Go home. Do you want to turn into ashes?!
灰にされてえのか！
W-Why?
な なんで？
なんで こんな所に…｡
Why are you here? Why did you come all the way here?
なんで こんな所まで！
ﾎﾞｸのことは もういいって…➡
Didn't I tell you to forget all about me?
もう好きに生きていこう って
言ったじゃないか！
I said we should live however we wanted to.
言われなくてもなぁ➡
You didn't have to tell us that. We're already living the way we want to.
こちとら とっくに
好きに生きてんだよ！
好きで ここに来てんだよ！
We came here because we wanted to.
We came here to be with you.
(新八/神楽)
好きで ｱﾝﾀと一緒にいんだよ!!
《なんで… どうしてだ？》
Why? I don't get it.
((お妙:ちゃらんぽらんな
銀さんより➡
The Gin-san right now seems a lot more serious than that worthless Gin-san...
今のほうが ﾏｼﾞﾒそうだし…))
《ちゃらんぽらんと
呼ばれていながら…》
They called me a worthless man.
((山崎:ｱﾝﾀ 確かに ふだんは
ちゃらんぽらんでしたがね))
I mean, not about you being a degenerate.
Why am I...
《なんで ﾎﾞｸは…｡
Why are they all...
なんで みんな…》
♪♪～
あっ！
here?
《なんで…》
♪♪～
ｶﾞｷは すっこんでな｡
死にてえのか？
You kids stay out of this. Do you want to die?
あんだと？ ﾃﾒｴもｶﾞｷだろ！
What?! You're a kid, too!
なんなんすか？ いったい｡
What's with you guys anyway?
I don't like it, but it's our job. We have to protect ordinary citizens.
不本意だが 仕事の都合上➡
一般市民は
守らなきゃいかんのでね｡
(土方)そういうことだ！
撃ちたきゃ ｵﾚたち 撃て！
What about it, Mr. Viper? If you want to fire, fire on us all.
ﾁﾝ砲だか ﾏﾝ砲だか知らねえが
毛ほども効かねえよ！
I don't care if it's the Chin Cannon
そうだ 撃ってみろ ｺﾗ！
この ﾘｽﾄﾗ侍が！
That's right. Shoot at us, Mr. Laid-off cop!!
(神楽)ﾊｹﾞ！ ﾘｽﾄﾗﾊｹﾞ!!
Baldy! Downsized baldy!
ｵﾚが いつ ﾊｹﾞたぁ!?
Since when was I bald?!
上等だ！ 江戸を消す前に
ﾃﾒｴらから消してやるよ！
All right! I'll wipe you away before I wipe away Edo!
私たち消す前に
お前 消してやるね～！
Before you wipe us out...
We'll... Wipe you out!
(土方)いけぇ！
Go!
早く撃て！
ﾁｬｰｼﾞには まだ時間が！
Quickly, fire!
We still need... Time to charge!
ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲだ！
ﾔﾂらを これ以上 近づけるなぁ!!
The Justaway!! Don't let them get any closer!
♪♪～
まだか？
Is it ready yet?!
Shinpachi, you brought my wooden sword with you, didn't you?
新八！ 木刀 持ってきたろうな？
え… あっ はい！
Huh? Oh... Yes.
Boss.
工場長！ すんませ～ん！
Sorry but I'm handing in my resignation.
今日で 辞めさせてもらいま～す！
ぎ… 銀さん！
銀ちゃん！
G-Gin-san!!
G-Gin-chan!!
Sorry, but...
悪いが ｵﾚは やっぱり…➡
I'm better at...
こっちのほうが 向いてるらしい！
being a free agent.
(ﾏﾑｼ)死ね～！ 坂田～!!
Die... Sakata!!
てやぁ～!!
♪♪～
お世話になりました｡
Thank you for helping me out.
(爆発音)
♪♪～
帰るぞ～｡
Let's go home.
♪♪～
ﾊﾊ… やっぱ ｱｲﾂらは
あれじゃないと… ねっ 局長！
That's how I like to see him. Right, Chief?
ｷﾐは 誰だ？
Who are you?
ああ～っ!!
♪♪～
[Preview]
Gin-san is back!
My memory has come back, but the Odd Jobs has been demolished!
Huh?
Unkei and Kaikei, the delivery carpenters?
I never asked for them! I want someone else!
The next episode: "Mistaking Someone's Name Is Rude!"
[It will require a lot of power to fix the Odd Jobs.]
[So hammer with us. Come on.]
A round of applause for Gin-chan and the gang for giving it their all again today!
今日もがんばった
銀さんたちに拍手～！